Email: maulika26@gmail.com

Tel: +1(705)229-4107 Address: Toronto, ON

# **SUMMARY**

### COMPUTER PROGRAMMER/ FULL STACK DEVELOPER/ WEB DEVELOPER

Solid in design and incorporation with natural critical thinking aptitudes with hands-on experience of more than 2 years. Capable in Ruby on Rails, ReactJs, JavaScript, Photoshop, and SQL. Energetic about executing and propelling new ventures. Capacity to make an interpretation of business prerequisites into specialized arrangements. Hoping to begin the profession as an Entrylevel programming engineer with a presumed firm determined by innovation. Strong support professional with a bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering and College Diploma from Georgian College.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Moments May 2020 - Present

- Creating a website for a client based on photography work.
- Used HTML5/CSS3/Bootstrap, firebase, and ReactJs for project environment.
- Resolve complex technical design issues.
- Analyze user requirements and convert requirements to design documents.
- Communicate effectively and professionally in all forms of communication with Client and team members

# **Front-End Developer co-op**

May 2018 - August 2018

Print1

- Worked in different designing tools like Photoshop, Illustrator to create a design.
- Made designs using coding in HTML5/CSS3 and JavaScript for websites.
- Worked with a group of planners and designers to satisfy customers' needs and making responsive web design using media queries.
- Fixed existing bugs in the application.
- Learned how to work under pressure.
- Documented recommended system changes through the ticketing system.

# **Software Developer**

September 2016 - August 2017

Kalp Corporate

- Used HTML5, CSS, AngularJs, EmberJs, and Git for API-based business website advancement.
- Participated in requirement gathering and analysis.
- Helped senior developers in a complex design project for corporate clients.
- Thoroughly studied and understood the event module and its mechanism.
- Help all individuals from the relegated office with everyday tasks and uncommon ventures.
- Provide essential degrees of exertion related to work requests.
- Communicate with area specialists, clients, and executives all through the product advancement lifecycle.

Email: maulika26@gmail.com

Tel: +1(705)229-4107 Address: Toronto, ON

# **Intern Software Developer**

July 2016 - September 2016

Atharva System

- Participate in scheduled events and Complete intern Group project(s), other duties as assigned.
- Perform troubleshoot and execution examination of code and frameworks
- Helped with backend development using Ruby on Rails, web development using HTML/CSS/JavaScript, and database SQL.
- Strong passion demonstrated via energy levels, enthusiasm, creativity, and commitment.

#### **Customer Service**

January 2019 - Present

A&W Restaurant, North York, Canada

- Provide excellent service and ensures that all customers were well taken care of.
- Delivering exceptional, fast and friendly service.
- Tasked with Manager responsibilities around customer satisfaction, management, and credit.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Knowledge: ReactJs, RoR, AngularJs, JavaScript, XML, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, macOS.

Database: MySQL, mongo DB

Others: GIT, Object-Oriented Principals and design patterns, Model-View-

Controller (MVC), Software Development Life Cycle, Great

knowledge of Mathematics, Microsoft Office Suite

#### **EDUCATION**

# Georgian College, Barrie

September 2017 – August 2019

Computer Programming - College Diploma (3.7 GPA)

# Gujarat Technological University, India

August 2012 - May 2016

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Engineering (3.3 GPA)

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Secure college Dean's list throughout all semesters of the Georgian college.

**Portfolio:** <a href="https://maulikadesai.netlify.app/">https://maulikadesai.netlify.app/</a>